Guide to the Bernard Berg Collection RG.065
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Bernard Berg Collection
1965-1968
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
RG.065
.5 Linear Feet 1 manuscript box
This collection contains sections of the Apollo Operations Handbook, as well as Polytech alum, Bernard Berg's, computation notebook from his time as an electrical engineer at Grumman Aerospace Corporation. The handbook contains information on the spacecraft, subsystems data, controls, displays, and the index.
Good. Some pages of the Handbook are ripped. There are pages pasted to the Computation Notebook, but all look fine for now.
Box 1
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Joel Berg, son of Bernard Berg, in 2025. The accession number associated with this gift is 2025-006.
Arrangement
This collection has been organized into two series: Series 1. Apollo Operations Handbook; Series 2. Computation Notebook. Folders arranged in chapter order.
Biographical / Historical
Bernard Berg attended Brooklyn Polytechnic from 1950-1954, taking undergraduate courses in electrical engineering and graduate courses in chemistry. Following his studies, Berg worked for the Gruuman Aerospace Corporation in Bethpage, Long Island as an electrical engineer from June 1963 to August 1968. He was tasked with designing the test equipment for the radars of the Apollo Lunar Excursion Module (LEM).
Scope and Contents
This collection contains sections of the Apollo Operations Handbook and one original lab notebook (computation notebook) from Polytech alum, Bernard Berg.
Aerospace engineering
- Series I: Apollo Operations Handbook
  - AOH: Section 1, Spacecraft, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.1, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.2, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.3, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.4, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.5, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.6, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.7, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.8, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.9, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.10, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - AOH: Section 2/2.11, Subsystems Data, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - AOH: Section 3, Controls and Displays, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - AOH Index, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series II: Computation Notebook, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Computation Notebook, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Item 1)